travelpost.com 2010-12-06

# TravelPost Privacy Policy

**TravelPost Privacy Policy**

 **Last Updated on May 7, 2010**

**1\. Overview**

The TravelPost Web site ("TravelPost", "we," or "us") is a community site containing hotel reviews, maps and information for millions of places around the world (collectively, the "Services"). We at TravelPost recognize that your privacy is important to you. We have created this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") to explain our privacy practices so you will understand when and how personally identifiable information is collected, used, disclosed and protected with respect to our Site. BY ACCESSING OUR SITE, YOU CONSENT TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY AS DESCRIBED HEREIN.

**The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you of the following:**

  * What kind of information does TravelPost collect about you? 
  * How will the information that TravelPost collects be used? 
  * With whom does TravelPost share the information it collects about you? 
  * What are the opt-out choices TravelPost provides you with regarding the collection, use, and distribution of your information? 
  * What security procedures does TravelPost use to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information collected by the company? 
  * How long does TravelPost retain information about me?
  * Does TravelPost collect information from children? 
  * How can I access the information TravelPost has about me or correct it? 
  * Notification of Changes 

**2\. What kind of information does TravelPost collect about you?**

We collect two basic types of information from our Site. Personally identifiable information is information that is directly associated with a specific person or entity such as a user's name, e-mail address, or information about activities that is directly linked to that person.

Our definition of personally identifiable information does not include "aggregate" information. Aggregate information is data we collect about a group or category of services or user from which individual user identities have been removed. Aggregate data may include anonymous demographic information such as country of origin, citizenship, ZIP code, age, gender, preferences and survey information. In other words, how you use our Site may be collected and combined with information about how others use the Site, but no personal information will be included in the resulting data. Aggregate data helps us understand trends and our user's needs so that we can better consider new features or otherwise tailor our Site.

The choice of how much personally identifiable information you disclose to us is completely at your discretion. Some areas of our Site are accessible without registration of any kind, and you can browse those areas of our Site. Other areas of our Site require registration in order for you to participate in the services offered. It is not mandatory for you to register and provide information to us, but please realize that in order for us to serve you better or provide particular features, you will need to provide certain information to access some areas of our Site. We collect information you give us when you register at and use our Site.

Specific examples of the information we collect include the following:

> **A. Registration Information.** When you register at our Site, we may collect various kinds of contact information about you including your name, e-mail address, date of birth, and other personally identifiable information.

> **B. TravelPost Profile, Postings and Reviews.** Please note that information and content that you post on our Site by using our services including, but not limited to, reviews, blogs and photos as well as your screen ID and information in your TravelPost profile can be viewed by the general public, and also may be stored on our systems indefinitely. You should not post any personally identifiable information that you do not wish to make publicly available.

> **C. Submissions and Customer Service.** From time-to-time we may post surveys, contests or sweepstakes on our site, which may request personally identifiable information, demographic information and/or customer feedback. Contests may require contact information or other demographic or personally identifiable information in order to determine eligibility. We may use information collected from surveys and contests to notify and contact winners of those contests. Participation in these requests is completely voluntary and with each request you will have the choice of whether or not to participate and disclose information. Also, we may collect information that identifies you personally when you send us comments, questions or suggestions.

> **D. Cookies and Passive Data Collection.** We automatically receive certain types of information whenever you interact with our Site. For example, when you visit the Site, our systems automatically collect standard user information and clickstream data for all users, including a user's IP address, operating system, and page views. Information may be automatically collected through the use of "cookies" which are discussed in more detail below. Cookies are small text files placed on your hard drive by a web site when you visit. These files identify your computer and record your preferences and other data about your visit so that when you return to the site, the site knows who you are and can personalize your visit. In general, we may use cookies to collect information so that we can determine how to improve our site by seeing which areas and features are most popular, to personalize the site and improve the site experience. Cookies are not tied to your personally identifiable information. Most browsers automatically accept cookies as the default setting. You can modify the setting to reject cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the sites you visit by editing browser options. If you decide not to accept our cookies, you will still be able to access those parts of our site available to the general public but you may not be able to use some of the site's features or services and you may have a less satisfactory experience.

> **E. Clear Gifs.** We and the companies that serve advertisements on our Site use a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that helps inform us and them about what content is active. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web user. Clear gifs are not tied to your personally identifiable information. Clear gifs are invisible on the page and very small, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear Gifs can "work with" existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same website or advertising company. That means, for example, that if a person visited "www.companyX.com", which uses an advertising company's clear gif, the website would read the clear gif's identifier and the advertising company's cookie ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer. The information would then go back to the advertising company. In addition, we use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails, to let us know which emails have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to know how well customers respond to certain communications.

> **F. Third Party Links and Ad Servers.** We provide links to third party websites, which may, or may not, use cookies, pixel tags and web tags. We also allow other companies, called third-party ad servers, to display advertisements on TravelPost.com. Ad servers may also use these tools to compile information about where users saw particular advertisements, and to determine which ads were clicked on. We are not responsible for, or have any control over, the privacy policies of those third party websites and ad servers, and encourage all users to read the privacy policies of each and every website visited when linking directly from TravelPost.

**3\. How will the information that TravelPost collects be used?**

In general, we use personal information to serve our users, enable them to take maximum advantage of our services and to improve the products and services we provide to you. For example, we may use personal information to contact our users relating to their registration to our service, to anticipate and resolve problems with our Site, to respond to customer support inquiries, and to send other TravelPost administrative and systems-related messages. We reserve the right to send such communications to our users without offering the opportunity to opt-out of receiving them. We do not send advertisements, newsletters, or any other commercial solicitations to our users.

**4\. With whom does TravelPost share the personal information it collects about you?**

We do not rent, sell, or share your personal information with third parties or nonaffiliated companies, except as described in this section or with your express permission.

  * We share trend and aggregate information with our partners for business purposes and with other third parties for marketing purposes. We might disclose, for example, that a certain percentage of our users list their home airport as San Francisco. However, this aggregated information is in no way traceable to any specific personal information.
  * We disclose information when required by law or judicial authority.
  * We disclose information as required to safeguard TravelPost's rights or property.
  * We reserve the right to share certain personal information (such as your log-in, profile, and preference information) with other websites that are owned and/or operated by TravelPost, Inc. These sites are also required to adhere to the provisions of this Privacy Policy until such time as it was amended in accordance with the process for modification set forth herein.
  * If TravelPost is ever merged with another company, or if TravelPost buys, sells or reorganizes some or all part(s) of its business, parties involved in such a transaction would gain access to the information that TravelPost has collected over time. Such third parties would be required, however, to adhere to the provisions of this Privacy Policy until such time as it was amended in accordance with the process for modification set forth herein.

**5\. What are the opt-out choices TravelPost provides you with regarding the collection, use, and distribution of your information?**

We reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to your registration with our service and TravelPost's other services, such as customer service responses and other administrative messages, without offering you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving them. You can opt-out from receiving such messages by canceling your registration with TravelPost. We reserve the right to send you advertisements, newsletters, and any other commercial solicitations to our users. You can opt-out from receiving this kind of communication in your profile settings.

Third parties may independently collect information about users when users choose to view links or ads displayed on TravelPost. Users should contact those third parties directly if they do not wish to receive communications from them, or do not want those third parties to collect information about them.

We are opposed to spam and our [Terms of Service](http://www.travelpost.com/tos.aspx) expressly prohibit users from uploading, posting, emailing, transmitting or otherwise making available junk mail, commercial advertisements, or other form of commercial solicitation on the TravelPost website or through TravelPost's services. Any violation of our policies, by sending unsolicited email advertisements to or through TravelPost's computer systems, will result in the sender being blocked from use of the Site and may subject the sender and his or her agents to civil and criminal penalties.

**6\. What security procedures does TravelPost use to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information collected by the company?**

TravelPost uses industry standard security measures to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Although we make good faith efforts to store the information collected by the TravelPost website in a secure operating environment that is not available to the public, we cannot guarantee complete security. Further, while we make every effort to ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee that our security measures will prevent third-party "hackers" from illegally obtaining this information.

Your account information is accessible online only through the use of a password. To protect the confidentiality of personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. You are responsible for all uses of our web site by any person using your password. Please advise us immediately if you believe your password has been misused.

**7\. How long does TravelPost retain information about me?**

TravelPost will retain information from which it is possible to identify you for a reasonable time bearing in mind the possibility of your re-using the Service. If you would like your information to be deleted at any time you should contact us using the details set out below.

**8\. Does TravelPost collect information from children?**

TravelPost.com is intended solely for use by persons 13 years of age or older. All persons under 13 years of age are prohibited from registering on TravelPost.

**9\. How can I access the information TravelPosthas about me or correct it?**

Registered users may, at any time, choose to correct or update the account information they have submitted to us. This may be done by logging into the site, clicking the My Account link, clicking the Edit Account link or Edit Profile Info and editing the information on these pages. Registered users may, at any time, chose to cancel their registration with TravelPost by sending an email to [contact@travelpost.com](mailto:contact@travelpost.com) and requesting TravelPost to close their account.

**10\. Notification of Changes**

From time to time, we may need to update our Privacy Policy because of changes in the law, in technology, in our business, or in our attempts to better serve your needs. If we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy, we will post a notification on our Site and update the effective date above. All amended terms shall automatically be effective 30 days after they are initially posted on the Site. Therefore, we encourage you to check the date of our privacy policy whenever you visit this Site to see if it has been updated since your last visit.

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy or personal information you have provided to us, please email us at [contact@travelpost.com](mailto:contact@travelpost.com) or contact us by mail at:

Postal Mail Address:   
TravelPost, Inc.  
401 2nd Ave. S, Suite 500  
Seattle, WA 98104  
Attention: Privacy Officer   

Further information about TravelPost is available at About TravelPost.com.
